STEPHEN GAVIN SEARS

370 Lancaster Ave., Haverford, Pennsylvania 19041 ● 563-340-8754 ● searssgavin@gmail.com ● https://gavin-sears.github.io/sgavinsears/

Profile:

Future graduate student in Computer Graphics and game technology at University of Pennsylvania. Computer Science Major and Visual Studies Minor at Haverford College. Experienced with coding and software design in Python, C#, Java, C++, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Strong writer and communicator with academic experience in computer graphics, machine learning, data science, and data structures and algorithms. Work experience with C#, Unity, Blender, Microsoft Office, Microsoft SQL. Strong IT services skills.

Education:

Computer Science Major & Visual Studies Minor - Haverford College, Haverford, PA

Aug. 2021-Present

Relevant Coursework:

Machine Learning, Computer Graphics, Game Design, Analysis of Algorithms, Data Science, Introduction to Data Structures, Discrete Mathematics, Computer Organization, Encoding Music, Multivariable Calculus, Theory and Practice of Exhibit

Work Experience:

Digital Scholarship Project Assistant - Bryn Mawr College, Ardmore, PA (10-14 hrs/week)

Sep. 2023-Dec. 2023

- Tested a project on the Oculus Quest used in a Bryn Mawr College student's thesis.
- Optimized 3D models in Blender by editing shaders, baking textures, and decimating objects.

Incubator Fellow - Haverford College, Haverford, PA (35 hrs/week)

Jun. 2023-Jul. 2023

- Co-founded a game studio, Lemon Dragon, to produce Word Wizard, an English language learning video game, with a team of developers.
- Scripted and designed dynamic UI systems for reading comprehension games using C# in Unity.
- Managed and troubleshot file repositories in Github using command line and GitHub desktop.
- Utilized 3D modeling, texturing, and shading to create ready-to-use game assets
- AGILE scrum

Software Engineer & Systems/Hardware IT Specialist - Sears Mfg. Co., Davenport, IA (40 hrs/week) Jun. 2022-Aug. 2022

- Worked on MVC format web-based applications by utilizing Microsoft SQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, C#, PHP, and Azure DevOps
- Troubleshot project issues by correcting payroll information in test software, which reportedly was accurate to the cent when referenced.
- Stood in for IT and Hardware specialists

Systems/Hardware IT Specialist - Sears Mfg. Co., Davenport, IA (40 hrs/week)

Aug. 2020-Aug. 2021

- Reimaged and replaced memory in 150 PCs company wide
- Worked extensively with Windows 7 and Windows 10 Systems
- Managed factory production flow via Manage 2000 MRP Personal Workstation
- Stood in for IT and Hardware specialists

Service and Leadership Experience:

Co-Head of the Bi-Co Computer Graphics Club - Haverford College, Haverford, PA

Sep. 2023-Present

- Managed funding requests and worked with a team to make important club decisions
- Recruited members through classes and personal connections
- Planned to teach workshops on 3D modeling in Blender, Unity, C++ OpenGL, and more. Also planned to assist with other workshops.

Percentage Project - Greater Philadelphia Area, Philadelphia, PA

Sep. 2023-Present

- Distributing and collecting feedback surveys on computer science courses at Haverford College.
- Planning spring social media campaign to boost participation.

Professional Development:

Languages: approximated A2 French Language Skills, Elementary proficiency Indonesian

Programming Languages: Python, Java, C#, C++, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, swift, Microsoft SQL

Libraries: Pandas, Matplotlib, Networkx, Pygame (Python), Unity Scripting (C#), OpenGL (C++), JQuery, Three.js (Javascript), Scenekit

Software: Unity, Blender, Maya, Microsoft Office, Xcode, Latex, Markdown